Nancy Hale Papers, 1908-1989
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES VII. WRITINGS
  - Children's
    - Stories
      - Untitled: drafts and notes undated (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Book: The Night of the Hurricane (Coward, McCann & Geoghegan) 1978
      - Notes (Box 39, Folder 12)
      - First draft (Box 39, Folder 13)
      - Middle version (Box 39, Folder 14)
      - Final draft (Box 39, Folder 15-16)
    - Correspondence
      - Miscellaneous manuscript pieces (Box 39, Folder 17)
      - Reviews 1978 (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Plays
    - "The Best of Everything" 1952
      - Typescript with notes (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Typescript, final version (Box 40, Folder 2)
      - Scrapbook with correspondence, photographs, and reviews (Box 40, Folder 3)
      - Program, clippings, and slides (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - "Somewhere She Dances" 1953
      - Typescript, first version (Box 40, Folder 5)
      - Typescript, later version (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Poems
    - 1928-34 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - undated (early career) (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - 1941-66 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - undated (later career) (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Stories
    - "Absolutely No Psychology": draft 1955 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - "Abuse": draft 1985 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - "An Age for Action" (Ladies Home Journal, Mar 1965): draft and published version 1963, 1965 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - "All Anybody" drafts and published version (Georgia Review, Spring 1966): 1966 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - "Animals in the House" (Harper's Magazine, Sep 1966): drafts and published version1965, 1966 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - "Are Writers Crazy?": typescript undated (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - "An Arrangement in Parents" (New Yorker, 22 Jun 1968): notes, drafts, and published version1966, 1968 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - "Artist": clipping and drafts 1983 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - "Artists Life": draft 1966 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - "At Sea": draft 1964 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - "The Barkley Boy": typescript undated (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - "The Barn" (New Yorker, 22 Dec 1956): draft 1956 (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - "The Battle of New Market": published version 1978 (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - "The Battle of the Supermarket": draft 1977 (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - "Between Rooms": drafts, typescript 1968 (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - "Between the Dark and the Daylight" (New Yorker, 16 Nov 1940; and Parents' Magazine, Oct 1965): published version 1940, 1965 (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - "A Bit of the Real England": drafts 1968 (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - "Book Review" (Harper's Bazaar, 1 Mar 1941): published version 1941 (Box 41, Folder 18)
    - "Bright Star in Darkness": drafts undated (Box 41, Folder 19)
    - "But as Yesterday": typescript undated (Box 41, Folder 20)
    - "Cab, Taxi" (New Yorker, 4 Oct 1941): published version 1941 (Box 41, Folder 21)
    - "The Carthaginian Rose" (Ladies Home Journal, Feb 1937): published version 1937 (Box 41, Folder 22)
    - "Ceremony of Innocence," (Virginia Quarterly Review, 1976): typescript published version 1976 (Box 41, Folder 23)
    - Club Car" (New Yorker, 1931): published version 1931 (Box 41, Folder 24)
    - "The Coasts of New England (New Yorker, 10 Sep 1955): galleys 1955 (Box 41, Folder 25)
    - "Colloque Sentimentale" (Scribners', Aug 1931): published version 1931 (Box 41, Folder 26)
    - "Comes the Revolution": draft 1934 (Box 41, Folder 27)
    - "The Coming of Age": drafts 1987 (Box 41, Folder 28)
    - "The Consent of the Governed": drafts 1965 (Box 41, Folder 29)
    - "A Curious Lapse" (New Yorker, 1 Aug 1959): draft and published version 1959 (Box 41, Folder 30)
    - "Death of an Artist": notes and drafts 1966 (Box 41, Folder 31)
    - "Distracted/Young": drafts 1977 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - "The Doctor": drafts 1984 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - "The Double House" (Vanity Fair, Apr 1934): published version 1934 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - "Dreams of Rich People," 1969 (McCalls, Aug 1972): drafts 1972 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - "The Earliest Dreams" (American Mercury, Apr 1934): published version 1934 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - "The Empress's Ring" (New Yorker, 10 Apr 1954): published version 1954 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - "England Is in the Eye of the Beholder": drafts 1965 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - "English Speaking Union": drafts undated (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - "Ensnared": draft 1977 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - "Entrance Into Life" (New Yorker, 14 Jun 1941): published version, proof 1941 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - "Ever Let the Fancy" (New Yorker, 31 Mar 1956): published version (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - "The Evidence": drafts 1966 (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - "Expression in Anima(?)": draft undated (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - "Eyes and No Eyes; Or, the Art of Seeing," 1965 (New Yorker, 20 Nov 1965): notes and drafts 1965 (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - "The Facts of Life" (Confrontation, Spring/Summer 1978): published version 1978 (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - "Family Groups": draft 1968 (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - "Family Ties" (Southern Review, Spring 1966): notes, drafts, and published version 1966 (Box 42, Folder 17)
    - "Far Out": drafts 1968 (Box 42, Folder 18)
    - "Fists Across the Sea" (New Yorker, 16 Jan 1960): typescripts 1960 (Box 42, Folder 19)
    - "Flotsam" (New Yorker, 5 Sep 1959): draft and published version 1959 (Box 42, Folder 20)
    - "Flower Show": notes and draft 1970 (Box 42, Folder 21)
    - "For Art's Sake" (New Yorker, 31 Mar 1934): published version 1934 (Box 42, Folder 22)
    - "George" (Vanity Fair, Mar 1934): published version 1934 (Box 42, Folder 23)
    - "The Ghost of Anne": typescript undated (Box 42, Folder 24)
    - "A Gift From the Shops" (New Yorker, 11 Nov 1961): draft, clipping and photograph 1961 (Box 42, Folder 25)
    - "The Girl with the Goat Cart" (New Yorker, 30 Nov 1963): draft 1963 (Box 42, Folder 26)
    - "The Girl Who Looked Like Garbo" (Vanity Fair, Oct 1931): published version 1931 (Box 42, Folder 27)
    - "Glamor-Glamor": drafts undated (Box 42, Folder 28)
    - "A Good Light," 1966 (New Yorker, 28 Sep 1968): drafts and published version 1968 (Box 42, Folder 29)
    - "Good Simple People": typescript undated (Box 42, Folder 30)
    - "The Good Things of Life" (New Yorker, 11 Dec 1954 as Lee Alderman): typescript, galley proof, and correspondence 1954 (Box 42, Folder 31)
    - "Grape Jelly": drafts 1966 (Box 42, Folder 32)
    - "The Great Grandmother" (New Yorker, 7 Dec 1935): published version 1935 (Box 42, Folder 33)
    - "The Great Houses": notes and drafts 1968 (Box 42, Folder 34)
    - "Halloween" (New Yorker, 2 Nov 1940): published version 1940 (Box 42, Folder 35)
    - "Handsome, Alert, a Real Young Blade" (Vogue, May 1962): draft 1962 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - "A Haunting" (New Yorker, 26 Oct 1957): published version 1957 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - "The Hit," (Arthur Winthrop Harcourt pseudonym?): typescript undated (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - "Illusion": draft 1963 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - "I'm Sorry," draft, undated (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - "In a Penthouse": typescripts undated (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - "In a Word" (New Yorker, 27 Jul 1963): drafts (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - "In the Porch": draft 1985 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - "Inheriting a Garden," 1966 (New Yorker, 18 May 1968): notes, drafts, and published version 1968 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - "In-Laws": drafts 1971 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - "The Innocent": drafts and published version 1963 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - "Inside" (New Yorker, 12 Dec 1953): published version 1953 (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - "The Interior": published version 1977 (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - "In Training/Little Girls": draft 1976 (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - "An Introduction to Glamor" (New Yorker, 2 Mar 1957): draft 1957 (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - "Journeys" (Virginia Quarterly Review, 1967): drafts 1967 (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - "Joyous Gard," 1967 (New Yorker, 12 Oct 1968): notes, drafts, and published version 1968 (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - "A Judgment": notes and drafts 1966 (Box 43, Folder 18)
    - "The Key Glorious": published version 1919 (Box 43, Folder 19)
    - "A Kind of Death": notes and draft undated (Box 43, Folder 20)
    - "The King of Fancy's Daughter" (New Yorker, 27 Apr 1956): draft and published version 1956 (Box 43, Folder 21)
    - "A Lady Travelling Alone": drafts 1961 (Box 43, Folder 22)
    - "Let Go, Let Go": published version undated (Box 43, Folder 23)
    - "Life for the City(?)": draft undated (Box 43, Folder 24)
    - "Likeness": notes and drafts 1967 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - "A Little Girl of Long Ago": notes and drafts 1984 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - "The Marching Feet" (New Yorker, 14 Jun 1941): published version 1941 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - "Mariana" (Harper's Monthly Magazine, Feb 1936): published version 1936 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - "Mary Ann": drafts undated (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - "Memory": drafts undated (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - "Mrs. Harcourt's Mare" (New Yorker, 28 Jul 1962): draft 1962 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - "Miss Dugan": drafts 1985 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - "Miss Smith from Jackson City": draft 1939 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - "Mr. Britton" (New Yorker, 1934?): published version 1934? (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - "Mr. Hamilton" (Michigan Quarterly Review, spring 1970): published version 1970 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - "Monster" (Red Book, 1939?): published version 1939? (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - "The Most Elegant Drawing Room in Europe" 1966 (New Yorker, 17 Sep 1966, O. Henry Memorial Prize Stories for 1968): drafts and published version 1966 (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - "Mother Country": draft undated (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - "The Mutual Friend or Too Many Cooks Spoil the Cook" 1926: draft 1926 (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - "My Mother's Clothes/The Black Cape" (Ladies Home Journal, 1966): drafts and published version 1963 (Box 44, Folder 16)
    - "My Mother's Solitudes," 1965 (New Yorker, 6 Mar 1965): draft 1965 (Box 44, Folder 17)
    - "My Own Little Beecher": draft undated (Box 44, Folder 18)
    - "A New Place" (New Yorker, 3 May 1958): published version 1958 (Box 44, Folder 19)
    - "No One My Grief Can Tell" (American Mercury, Oct 1932): published version 1932 (Box 44, Folder 20)
    - "No Other Gods" (New Yorker, 1 Sep 1945): published version 1945 (Box 44, Folder 21)
    - "Notes on the Machine Age": draft undated (Box 44, Folder 22)
    - "O True Apothecary!": draft 1934 (Box 44, Folder 23)
    - "Old Fashioned Girl": draft undated (Box 44, Folder 24)
    - "On the Cow Hill's End": draft undated (Box 44, Folder 25)
    - "Order" (Harper's Monthly Magazine, Aug 1936): published version 1936 (Box 44, Folder 26)
    - "Other People's Lives": drafts and notes 1963 (Box 44, Folder 27-28)
    - "The Other Side," 1967 (New Yorker, 1 Mar 1969): published version 1969 (Box 44, Folder 29)
    - "The Other Side of the Brook": draft undated (Box 44, Folder 30)
    - "Outside" (New Yorker, 29 Sep 1956): published version 1956 (Box 44, Folder 31)
    - "Painted Into a U-Corner": draft 1956 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - "Pajamas!": typescript undated (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - "A Part": drafts 1983 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - "The Pattern of Perfection" (New Yorker, 24 Dec 1955): published version 1955 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - "The Petals of a Flower": draft and typescript undated (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - "Pierce's" (New Yorker, 19 Nov 1955): published version, clippings 1955 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - "A Place to Hide In" (New Yorker, 14 Dec 1941): published version 1941 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - "The Poor Man's War Between the States," 1961 (New Yorker, 24 Mar 1964): draft and published version 1964 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - "The Presence of Children": notes and drafts 1966 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - "A Print of Venus": draft and typescript undated (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - "Private Madness": typescript undated (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - "Progress Report," (re: stroke): typescript undated (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - "Questions": drafts 1969-70? (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - "A Real Good Time": notes and drafts 1966 (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - "The Real Thing": galley 1979 (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - "Remembering": drafts undated (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - "Rich People" (New Yorker, 9 Jul 1960): draft 1960 (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - "Room for a Slip": draft undated (Box 45, Folder 18)
    - "Roots/Situation in Life": draft undated (Box 45, Folder 19)
    - "The Rule for Randall": typescript undated (Box 45, Folder 20)
    - "St. Valentine's Coming!": drafts 1984 (Box 45, Folder 21)
    - "The Search for New England": draft 1977 (Box 45, Folder 22)
    - "The Secret Secret," New Yorker, (31 Aug 1957): draft (Box 45, Folder 23)
    - "Seeing": drafts 1971 (Box 45, Folder 24)
    - "Separation" (Red Book, Jul 1940): published version 1940 (Box 45, Folder 25)
    - "A Separation": drafts 1967 (Box 45, Folder 26)
    - "She Stoops to Massachusetts": typescript undated (Box 45, Folder 27)
    - "The Signorina" (Transatlantic Review, Autumn 1965): published version 1964 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - "Simple Aveu" (Scribners', May 1932): published version 1932 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - "The Sisters": typescript undated (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - "A Slow Boat to China": published version undated (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - "Some Important Information to the Smart World": typescript undated (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - "A Story" undated (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - "The Story of Daphne" (Ladies Home Journal, May 1940): draft and published version 1940 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - "The Story of Jean Strecker": typescript undated (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - "A Summer's Long Dream" (New Yorker, 14 Jul 1956): published version 1956 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - "Sunday Lunch" (New Yorker, 8 May 1965; O. Henry Memorial Prize Stories for 1966): drafts, notes, clipping, and published version 1965 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - "Tastes": drafts and published version 1982 (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - "That Summer" (New Yorker, 6 Mar 1937): published version 1937 (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - "That Woman" (Harper's Monthly Magazine, Apr 1940): clippings 1940 (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - "There is a Host Approaching Nigh" (30 Nov 1957): draft and published version New Yorker 1957 (Box 46, Folder 14)
    - "This Place and Wherever You Are": draft 1961 (Box 46, Folder 15)
    - "The Three Wise Guys" (Dec 1931) Vanity Fair: published version 1931 (Box 46, Folder 16)
    - "To the Invader" (Modern Youth, Mar 1933): published version 1933 (Box 46, Folder 17)
    - "The Toimi": drafts 1987 (Box 46, Folder 18)
    - "Treasure": drafts 1969 (Box 46, Folder 19)
    - "The Unregenerate" (Vanity Fair, Jan 1934): published version 1934 (Box 46, Folder 20)
    - "Up on the North Shore": typescript undated (Box 46, Folder 21)
    - "La Vie en Gris": typescript undated (Box 46, Folder 22)
    - "The Village": drafts 1977 (Box 46, Folder 23)
    - "Waiting" (Virginia Quarterly Review, Autumn 1966): drafts and published version 1965 (Box 46, Folder 24)
    - "The Waxen Man" (American Mercury, Sep 1933): published version 1933 (Box 46, Folder 25)
    - "The Way They Wanted Her to Be" (Good Housekeeping, May 1946): published version 1946 (Box 46, Folder 26)
    - "What Haunts Thee in Fond Shapes," 1966 (New Yorker, 5 Aug 1967): notes, drafts, and published version 1967 (Box 46, Folder 27)
    - "White Poppies Die" (Vanity Fair, Aug 1933): published version 1933 (Box 46, Folder 28)
    - "Who Lived and Died Believing" (O. Henry Memorial Award Prize Stories of 1943): published version (Box 46, Folder 29)
    - "Who Needs No Introduction...": drafts 1979 (Box 46, Folder 30)
    - "Who Would Not Weep": typescript undated (late 1920s or early 1930s) (Box 46, Folder 31)
    - "Why Do They Do It?": draft 1977 (Box 46, Folder 32)
    - "The World Outside": drafts 1968 (Box 46, Folder 33)
    - "The World, the Flesh, and the Devil," 1966 (New Yorker, 27 Apr 1968): drafts and published version 1968 (Box 46, Folder 34)
    - "The Worst Years of Our Lives": draft undated (Box 46, Folder 35)
    - "You Can Go Home Again," (Venture, 1965): drafts, typescript, and published version 1965 (Box 46, Folder 36)
    - Untitled drafts, fragments, and notes
      - Elderly woman about to go into a nursing home undated (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Giverny undated (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Closing up a house undated (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - An older couple undated (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Preschool undated (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - Woman visiting a doctor in England undated (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - unidentified 1964-66 (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - unidentified 1969-70 (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - undated (Box 47, Folder 9-11)
      - Fragments undated (Box 47, Folder 12-14)
  - Books, [see also volumes on shelf]
    - Between the Dark and the Daylight (Charles Scribner's Sons, 1943): review 1943 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Black Summer 1963
      - Draft (Box 48, Folder 2-6)
      - Typescript (Box 48, Folder 7-12)
      - Notes and research material (Box 48, Folder 13-14)
      - Reviews, publicity, and book jacket (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - A Changing Faculty (unpublished) 1968-70
      - Draft (Box 49, Folder 1-6)
      - Unused text fragments (Box 49, Folder 7)
      - Final draft (Box 49, Folder 8-13)
      - Typescript with notes for rewrite
        - Chapter 1-2 (Box 49, Folder 14)
        - Chapter 3-end (Box 50, Folder 1-4)
    - Charlieshope (unpublished) 1966-81
      - First draft (Box 50, Folder 5-10)
      - Manuscript
        - Introduction to page 203 (Box 50, Folder 11-13)
        - Page 204 to end (Box 51, Folder 1-4)
      - Typescript
        - Introduction to page 498 (Box 51, Folder 5-13)
        - Page 499 to end (Box 52, Folder 1-3)
      - Correspondence (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - Notes re plot, structure, writing (Box 52, Folder 5)
        {see also box 65 Cassettes: notes for rewrites}
      - Notes, miscellaneous (Box 52, Folder 6)
      - Research material (Box 52, Folder 7-13)
      - Research material (Box 53, Folder 1-2)
    - Dear Beast 1959
      - Typescript (Box 53, Folder 3-6)
      - Reviews (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - The Earliest Dreams: reviews 1936 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - The Empress's Ring: notes and reviews 1955 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Heaven and Hardpan Farm: reviews 1957 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Leon Kroll: A Spoken Memoir, edited by Nancy Hale and Fredson Bowers 1983
      - Publicity, research, correspondence, and review (Box 53, Folder 11)
      - Typescript of essay by Nancy Hale (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - The Life in the Studio 1969
      - Drafts (Box 53, Folder 13)
      - "Foreword" draft (Box 53, Folder 14)
      - Paperback edition, Avon Books 1980 (Box 53, Folder 15)
      - Correspondence from readers 1969-71 (Box 53, Folder 16)
    - Mary Cassatt 1975
      - Manuscript (Box 54, Folder 1-5)
      - Manuscript (cont'd) (Box 55, Folder 1-8)
      - "Final" draft (Box 56, Folder 1-4)
      - "Complete" draft (Box 56, Folder 5-9)
      - Research and correspondence (Box 57, Folder 1)
      - Notes
        - General (Box 57, Folder 2)
        - For the beginning (Box 57, Folder 3)
        - On M.C.'s childhood (Box 57, Folder 4)
        - Old Philadelphia (Box 57, Folder 5)
        - Trouble with family (Box 57, Folder 6)
        - Misc. info on M.C. (Box 57, Folder 7-8)
        - Paris shows (Box 57, Folder 9)
        - Books M.C. read (Box 57, Folder 10)
        - Character of M.C. (Box 57, Folder 11)
        - Vanity (Box 57, Folder 12)
        - Understanding conflict (Box 57, Folder 13)
        - Collections and the rich (Box 57, Folder 14)
        - Politics (Box 57, Folder 15)
        - Feminism (Box 57, Folder 16)
        - Psychiatric material (Box 57, Folder 17)
        - Breakdown (Box 57, Folder 18)
        - Death and depression (Box 57, Folder 19)
        - Paranoia (Box 57, Folder 20)
        - Sex (Box 57, Folder 21)
        - Spiritual life (Box 57, Folder 22)
        - Webb letters (Box 57, Folder 23)
        - Re Beaufresne de l'Oise (Box 57, Folder 24)
        - 10 Rue de Marignan (Box 57, Folder 25)
        - Other personalities (Box 57, Folder 26)
        - For 'Art and Degas' (Box 57, Folder 27)
        - Barbizon School (Box 57, Folder 28)
        - Degas old (Box 57, Folder 29)
        - For 'The Fall' (Box 57, Folder 30)
        - Blindness (Box 57, Folder 31)
        - Epilogue (Box 57, Folder 32)
        - For correcting ms. (Box 57, Folder 33)
        - Misc. notes (Box 58, Folder 1)
        - Descriptions of pictures (Box 58, Folder 2)
        - From books read (Box 58, Folder 3)
        - Books unread (Box 58, Folder 4)
        - People to see about M.C. (Box 58, Folder 5)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 58, Folder 6)
      - Interview notes (Box 58, Folder 7)
      - Interviews
        - Mme. Adhemar, Director of Orangerie (Box 58, Folder 8)
        - Dupont, Durand-Ruel (Box 58, Folder 9)
        - Lindsay (Box 58, Folder 10)
        - Rouart, Scilly (Box 58, Folder 11)
      - Reviews (Box 58, Folder 12)
      - Clippings (Box 58, Folder 13)
      - Correspondence with editors 1975 (Box 58, Folder 14)
      - Correspondence from readers 1975-77 (Box 58, Folder 15)
      - Correspondence re M.C. 1975-76, undated (Box 58, Folder 16)
      - Book jackets 1987 (Box 58, Folder 17)
    - Never Any More: reviews 1934 (Box 58, Folder 18)
    - New England Discovery: An Anthology 1963
      - Correspondence with publishers (Box 59, Folder 1)
      - Introductory material (Box 59, Folder 2)
      - Editorial comments
        - 17th century (Box 59, Folder 3)
        - 18th century (Box 59, Folder 4)
        - 19th century (Box 59, Folder 5)
        - 20th century (Box 59, Folder 6)
      - Notes, selections, etc. (Box 59, Folder 7)
      - Notes on material not used (Box 59, Folder 8)
      - Reviews (Box 59, Folder 9)
      - Secretarial accounts (Box 59, Folder 10)
      - Illustrations
        - Correspondence, research, and permissions (Box 60, Folder 1-66)
        - Accounts 1962 (Box 60, Folder 67)
        - Acknowledgements and complimentary copies (Box 60, Folder 68)
        - Correspondence with publisher (Box 60, Folder 69)
        - Lists (Box 60, Folder 70)
        - Captions: drafts (Box 60, Folder 71)
        - Photographs and captions (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - A New England Girlhood: reviews 1958 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - The Night of the Hurricane (Box 61)
      [see Children's subseries above]
    - Georgia O'Keefe (proposed biography): research materials (Box 61, Folder 3-4)
    - The Pattern of Perfection: reviews 1960 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - The Prodigal Women 1942, 1969
      - Reviews (Box 61, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence 1969 (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - The Realities of Fiction 1962
      - Notes (Box 61, Folder 8)
      - Drafts (Box 61, Folder 9)
      - Typescript (Box 61, Folder 10-13)
      - Final typescript (Box 62, Folder 1-3)
      - Reprints (Box 62, Folder 4)
      - Reviews and publicity 1962, 1985 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - A Relating: The Personal Record of a Black Virginia Girlhood (unpublished) late 1980s?
      - Transcription of tapes (Box 63, Folder 1)
        {see also box 65: Cassettes: taped conversations between Annie Richardson and Nancy Hale}
      - Early draft (Box 63, Folder 2-3)
      - Research material (Box 63, Folder 4)
      - Notes and drafts (Box 63, Folder 5-6)
      - Version called "The Pursuit of Annie's Happiness" (Box 63, Folder 7)
      - Typescript (Box 63, Folder 8-9)
      - Typescript with notes for rewrite (Box 63, Folder 10-11)
    - Secrets 1971
      - Typescript (Box 64, Folder 1)
      - Reviews (Box 64, Folder 2)
      - Book jacket (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - The Sign of Jonah: reviews and publicity 1950 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Elinor Wylie (proposed edition of letters): correspondence and research material (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - The Young Die Good: reviews and publicity 1932 (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Untitled novel (unpublished)
      - First draft (Box 64, Folder 7)
      - Notes and research material (Box 64, Folder 8-9)